Daniel WOAGOU

Software Engineer, 29 years old, Togolese. Address:

Agoè Sogbossito, Lomé -Togo

Phone:

(+228) 91378364 / 97579764

Email:

daniel.woagou@gmail.com

LinkedIn:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/danipw/

Summary

Passionate Software Engineer specializing in .Net development. Experienced with all stages of the application development cycle. Well-versed in numerous programming languages including C#, Java, JavaScript, C/C++, Python. Strong background in project management and customer relations. I have good team leading skills and I have also taken numerous jobs alone.

Skill Highlights

- Project management
- Strong decision maker
- Complex problem solver

- Team leading
- Innovative
- Service-focused

Experience

Software Developer - 03/2021 to now

Togolese Revenue Office (OTR), Lomé-Togo.

Public administrative establishment, endowed with administrative and financial mana for collecting taxes, duties and customs duties on behalf of the State and local author

- Management of the tax payment platform:
 - ✓ Framing and design of the exchange protocols;
 - ✓ Management of the bank reconciliation interconnection dat
- Interconnecting CEET (National Electricity Supplier) and Togolese Resystems:
 - ✓ Framing and design of the exchange protocols;
 - ✓ Design and implementation of ETLs (Talend ESB);
 - ✓ Development of the exchange monitoring platform (PHP).
- Team lead for the digitalization of the workflows of the Land Regist the registration:
 - ✓ Development tasks;
 - ✓ Unit testing;
 - ✓ Debugging tasks;
 - ✓ Components upgrading or migration activities;

Web Migration Project Manager - 01/2017 to 02/2021 CERGI SA, Lomé-Togo

Banking IT solutions publisher. They offer an Enterprise Resource Planning system cal Information System), developed in ASP.NET, C # and VB6 and deployed in ECOWAS ar

Jobs History:

- Application developer: January 2017- December 2017

- Team Lead: December 2017 June 2018
- Project Manager: July 2018 February 2021
 - Development and testing of the new interoperability system with other banking ERPs for publishing reports under the Basel 2 & 3 standard (Periodic report, Prudential system, etc.)
 - Migration and Deployment of Core Banking for:
 - ✓ The Guarantee Fund for the Private Sector (MALI);
 - ✓ African Lease Togo.
 - Technological watch;
 - Coding of services and libraries for the transition from VB6 to the Web platform;
 - Training of developers over programming standards;
 - Evaluate the user's needs and set up the specifications;
 - Design and write technical specifications;
 - Determine and carry out the functional and technical test phases and procedures;
 - Study functional and technical problems and carry out technical and corrective compliance;
 - Manage and synchronize studies, implementation or IT development (Azure DevOps);
 - Software deployments and configurations;
 - Design of exchange protocols;
 - Development of automated Jobs for data extraction, processing and loading with Talend;
 - Setup and unit testing;
 - Carry out data approval and dress rehearsals;
 - Go Live.

Achievements

- CIS -TOGO organizational and technological audit mission.
- Design, development and deployment of "Lompogaal", a taxpayer directory management platform for the 17 municipalities of the savannah region.
- Design, development and deployment of "Police Help" (Second National Prize of the AppsTogo competition of the Ministry of the Digital Economy): identity control application, geolocation, observation and communication between police officers and their station (Web version in PHP and Mobile in Xamarin and Java Android).

Education

Bachelor of Science: **Computer Engineering** - 2016 **INSTITUT AFRICAIN D'INFORMATIQUE IAI-TOGO**, Lomé.

Languages

French - Native

English - B2 Business Vantage

Technical skills

Programming Languages: C#, Java, JavaScript, C/C++, Python

Databases: Microsoft SQL Server, Oracle, MySQL et PostgreSQL

Operating Systems: Microsoft Windows, Linux, MacOS, Android

ETL: **Talend**

Machine Learning: ML.NET

Activities and Interests

- Football
- Chess
- Science documentaries